<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Datica Company Blog</title>
  <id>https://datica.com/blog/</id>
  <subtitle>Thoughts from the team behind Healthcare's trusted cloud</subtitle>
  <link href="https://datica.com/blog/" rel="self"/>
  <author>
    <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
  </author>
  <icon>https://datica.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://images.contentful.com/189dvqdsjh46/4SwayIJ5AcCe4iCU820mQs/504b8e57eacc0d81032d01ace96bc622/datica_logo__black.png?w=150</logo>
  <updated>2018-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>2018 Healthcare Trends Part 3 — 6 Predictions for the Post-EHR World</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/2018-trends-6-predictions-post-ehr-world"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/2018-trends-6-predictions-post-ehr-world</id>
    <published>2018-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Travis Good, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this 3rd part of our 2018 Healthcare Trends series, Travis Good MD, CEO of Datica, offers a deep look at what we can expect to see in a post-EHR world.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the biggest winners in our post-health reform world (post-HITECH and ACA) are neither patients nor providers; the big winners are electronic health record (EHR) companies and the cottage industry of consultants and services who support them. This isn’t an indictment of EHRs, though I don’t think EHRs have delivered on the promise of the triple aim. It’s merely a sad observation of the outcome of billions of dollars spent to improve healthcare. Regardless, we are here in 2018, and EHRs play a central role in the daily lives of providers and, by extension, patients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this third part of our &lt;a href="https://datica.com/blog/6-healthcare-trends-to-watch-in-2018/"&gt;2018 Healthcare Trends&lt;/a&gt; series, I offer predictions of what we can expect to see in a post-EHR world.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Getting to Know Datica’s New Chief Technology and Security Officer — Christopher Gerg</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/getting-to-know-daticas-cto-and-cso-chris-gerg"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/getting-to-know-daticas-cto-and-cso-chris-gerg</id>
    <published>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The path toward becoming Datica’s new Chief Technology Officer and Chief Security Officer involved many twists and turns for Christopher Gerg.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The path toward Chief Technology Officer and even Chief Security Officer involves many twists and turns for those selected. As we see below, Christopher Gerg’s path also fits this winding route that leads some individuals to pursue one or more of the most important roles within a healthcare technology company. We’re honored that Chris has chosen Datica and wanted to share a small peek into his vast and interesting background.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What Exactly is a Digital Health Application?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/what-exactly-is-a-digital-health-application"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/what-exactly-is-a-digital-health-application</id>
    <published>2018-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Are digital health apps consumer-facing, or used in a clinical setting? How are they improving patient outcomes? How are digital health apps integrated into clinicians’ workflows?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Digital health is something of a buzzword in the industry right now, but evidence is emerging that digital health apps have the potential to both improve patient outcomes and &lt;a href="https://datica.com/blog/digital-health-apps-could-save-7-billion/"&gt;save money across the healthcare system&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Digital Health Apps Could Save the US $7 Billion</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/digital-health-apps-could-save-7-billion"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/digital-health-apps-could-save-7-billion</id>
    <published>2018-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Travis Good, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Digital health apps have been accompanied by plenty of hype, but a new report shows that the hype may be justified with $7 billion/year potential.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Digital health apps have been around for a few years, and have been accompanied by plenty of hype, but a new report shows that the hype may be justified — not because of innovation, but because such apps have the potential to save the US healthcare system as much as $7 billion annually.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Introducing Container Services: Deploy Custom Docker Images onto Datica</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/introducing-container-services-deploy-custom-docker-images"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/introducing-container-services-deploy-custom-docker-images</id>
    <published>2018-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;New! Customers deploy custom Docker images onto Datica to increase their productivity and make it much easier to debug their own applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s nearly impossible to be a part of a conversation among application or cloud developers today without somebody mentioning Docker or containers. Datica was an early adopter of Docker containers and, in fact, the Datica Platform has always been based on running Docker containers. Historically, use of Docker has been restricted to our “git push” model in which customers would push their code to Datica directly from their git repository and rely on our automated build process to build the code that would package that application for them.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Women in Cloud: New Support for Female Entrepreneurs</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/women-in-cloud-new-support-for-female-entrepreneurs"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/women-in-cloud-new-support-for-female-entrepreneurs</id>
    <published>2018-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-31T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Women and men all over the world are rising to the challenge of changing the male-dominated technology landscape. Just last week in Stockholm, the Women in Tech 2018 conference sold out completely in just two minutes after tickets went on sale.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Women and men all over the world are rising to the challenge of changing the male-dominated technology landscape. Just last week in Stockholm, the &lt;a href="https://www.womenintech.se/"&gt;Women in Tech 2018&lt;/a&gt; conference sold out completely in just two minutes after tickets went on sale. It seems that you can’t read today’s news without finding another story about women speaking out about gender injustices. Though women have made major strides forward on issues around equality, gender diversity in the workplace — especially at the top — remains an unattained goal.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title> 2018 Healthcare Trends Part 2: Cash-Pay Practices will Grow</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/2018-trends-cash-pay-practices-will-grow"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/2018-trends-cash-pay-practices-will-grow</id>
    <published>2018-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Travis Good, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Whether you call it cash pay, subscription medicine, direct primary care, or concierge medicine, cutting out the payors is 1 of 6 2018 trends Datica predicts.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Where is healthcare going in 2018? In the first article in this series, I outlined &lt;a href="https://datica.com/blog/6-healthcare-trends-to-watch-in-2018/"&gt;six trends for 2018&lt;/a&gt; I predict we’ll see as the government, individuals, and private sector demand change this year. The first of those trends is an increase in cash-pay practices. Whether you call it cash pay, subscription medicine, direct primary care, or concierge medicine, the underlying commonality is cutting out the payors.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title> HIPAA Enforcement in 2017: Key learnings from others’ mistakes</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/hipaa-enforcement-in-2017"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/hipaa-enforcement-in-2017</id>
    <published>2018-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;One thing is certain: healthcare still has a security problem. Out of 295 breaches reported so far for 2017, 132 are hacking/IT incident breaches.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The US Department of Health and Human Services’ (HHS) Office for Civil Rights (OCR) investigates reports of data breaches involving health information. The breach reports are publicly available and searchable with a tool called the &lt;a href="https://www.hhs.gov/about/news/2017/07/25/hhs-unveils-improved-web-tool-highlight-recent-breaches-health-information.html"&gt;HIPAA Breach Reporting Tool&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because entities have 60 days beyond the date a breach occurs to report it, complete results for 2017 will not be available until March 2018. However, a look at what has been reported so far, along with any general trends, may be instructive as we all prepare for the more stringent &lt;a href="https://datica.com/academy/gdpr-fines-and-penalties/"&gt;penalties of GDPR&lt;/a&gt; coming in May of 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The U.S. Healthcare System is like a Casino says Dan Munro</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/us-healthcare-is-like-a-casino-says-dan-munro"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/us-healthcare-is-like-a-casino-says-dan-munro</id>
    <published>2018-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Author Dan Munro thinks the US Healthcare system is like a casino. Learn why in these highlights from that enlightening Healthcare Innovators Podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dan Munro is the author of the book &lt;a href="http://dan-munro.com/book/"&gt;Casino Healthcare: The Health of a Nation: America’s Biggest Gamble&lt;/a&gt;. Though the book was published in 2016, not much has changed. Travis Good interviewed Munro for Datica’s &lt;a href="https://datica.com/innovation/dan-munro-healthcares-technology-gamble/"&gt;Healthcare Innovators Podcast&lt;/a&gt; on September 29, 2017. A few highlights of that enlightening conversation follow below, but make sure to listen to the recorded podcast to hear it all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Trusted Exchange Framework and the Pursuit of Interoperability</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/the-trusted-exchange-framework"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/the-trusted-exchange-framework</id>
    <published>2018-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The January, 2018 draft of the Trusted Exchange Framework is the first real step toward interoperability since the Cures Act was passed.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest obstacles to using electronic health data to the fullest potential is the lack of interoperability. At every level of healthcare, the lack of interoperability causes problems: patients cannot easily access their own health data, providers have problems accessing the health information of new patients, researchers cannot access the data necessary to identify trends that would improve population health, and technology companies struggle to compete in a closed marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
