<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Datica Company Blog</title>
  <id>https://datica.com/blog/</id>
  <subtitle>Thoughts from the team behind Healthcare's trusted cloud</subtitle>
  <link href="https://datica.com/blog/" rel="self"/>
  <author>
    <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
  </author>
  <icon>https://datica.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://images.contentful.com/189dvqdsjh46/4SwayIJ5AcCe4iCU820mQs/504b8e57eacc0d81032d01ace96bc622/datica_logo__black.png?w=150</logo>
  <updated>2018-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>The U.S. Healthcare System is like a Casino says Dan Munro</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/us-healthcare-is-like-a-casino-says-dan-munro"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/us-healthcare-is-like-a-casino-says-dan-munro</id>
    <published>2018-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Author Dan Munro thinks the US Healthcare system is like a casino. Learn why in these highlights from that enlightening Healthcare Innovators Podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Dan Munro is the author of the book &lt;a href="http://dan-munro.com/book/"&gt;Casino Healthcare: The Health of a Nation: America’s Biggest Gamble&lt;/a&gt;. Though the book was published in 2016, not much has changed. Travis Good interviewed Munro for Datica’s &lt;a href="https://datica.com/innovation/dan-munro-healthcares-technology-gamble/"&gt;Healthcare Innovators Podcast&lt;/a&gt; on September 29, 2017. A few highlights of that enlightening conversation follow below, but make sure to listen to the recorded podcast to hear it all.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Trusted Exchange Framework and the Pursuit of Interoperability</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/the-trusted-exchange-framework"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/the-trusted-exchange-framework</id>
    <published>2018-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The January, 2018 draft of the Trusted Exchange Framework is the first real step toward interoperability since the Cures Act was passed.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest obstacles to using electronic health data to the fullest potential is the lack of interoperability. At every level of healthcare, the lack of interoperability causes problems: patients cannot easily access their own health data, providers have problems accessing the health information of new patients, researchers cannot access the data necessary to identify trends that would improve population health, and technology companies struggle to compete in a closed marketplace.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>6 Healthcare Trends to Watch in 2018</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/6-healthcare-trends-to-watch-in-2018"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/6-healthcare-trends-to-watch-in-2018</id>
    <published>2018-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Travis Good, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Government, individuals, and private sector will continue a push for change in 2018. Dr. Travis Good predicts 6 major healthcare trends for the new year.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s 2018, and the world looks much different &lt;a href="https://datica.com/blog/2017-healthcare-trends-part-1-the-rise-of-patient-as-consumer/"&gt;than it did a year ago&lt;/a&gt;. Go &lt;a href="https://datica.com/blog/5-predictions-for-digital-health-in-2016/"&gt;back even further&lt;/a&gt; and the differences are even more stark. No place is that more evident than in healthcare. As the largest industry in the world, healthcare has  weathered the most significant political waves of the last fifteen years. As the costs of healthcare increased unchecked, politicians took notice.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>10 Most-Read Articles of 2017</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/10-most-read-articles-of-2017"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/10-most-read-articles-of-2017</id>
    <published>2018-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What was healthcare reading to stay on top of their technology game in 2017? Our top 10 blogs show cloud and compliance as top of mind for many of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What were healthcare developers and leaders reading to stay on top of their technology game in 2017? If the following list of top articles from the Datica blog is any indication, cloud and compliance were top of mind for many of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Q4 Industry Report: Shadow IT's positives and negatives within healthcare</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/q4-industry-report-shadow-its-positives-and-negatives-within-healthcare"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/q4-industry-report-shadow-its-positives-and-negatives-within-healthcare</id>
    <published>2017-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kris Gösser</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Datica’s Winter 2017 quarterly industry report examines the paradox of shadow IT in healthcare. Is it a security threat or enabler for innovation?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://datica.com/innovation/shadow-it-in-healthcare-cloud-cover-for-innovation-initiatives"&gt;The Winter installment of Datica’s quarterly industry report is now available&lt;/a&gt;. The report examines shadow IT as both a growing security threat to health IT, but also as a unique and unrivaled enabler for innovation when managed appropriately. Shadow IT as a topic is quite the paradox—this report tries to help make sense of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How does GDPR compare to HIPAA?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/how-does-gdpr-compare-to-hipaa"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/how-does-gdpr-compare-to-hipaa</id>
    <published>2017-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Travis Good, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Though different in who they apply to and how you prove compliance, HIPAA and GDPR are both about having security as a core tenet of operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the AWS re:Invent conference earlier this month, GDPR was a major area of interest from attendees though AWS has little content coverage for GDPR. GDPR, which stands for General Data Protection Regulation, is the acronym for the much anticipated new EU security and privacy framework that goes into effect in May of 2018. GDPR leaves some discretion to EU member states but, as a general rule, and the reason it is getting so much attention, is that it applies across all EU Member States. The purpose of this post is to introduce those familiar with healthcare privacy and security in the United States, namely those concerned with HIPAA, to GDPR. This post doesn’t get into technical requirements, or even security requirements more generally, but instead focuses on the broader principles and privacy guidelines for health data under GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why Let's Encrypt is our favorite open source project this year</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/why-lets-encrypt-is-our-favorite-open-source-project-this-year"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/why-lets-encrypt-is-our-favorite-open-source-project-this-year</id>
    <published>2017-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Rich</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This holiday season, we’re proud to support one of our favorite open source projects, Let’s Encrypt, in their mission to make the internet more secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We highly value open-source technology at Datica. We’re not only contributors to the open source community, but &lt;a href="https://datica.com/blog/announcing-one-click-installations-of-mirth-connect-and-open-source/"&gt;open source users&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://datica.com/open-source/"&gt;producers&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such open source project that we’re absolutely thrilled to be using is &lt;a href="https://letsencrypt.org/"&gt;Let’s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Let’s Encrypt&lt;/em&gt; is a completely free and open source certificate authority. Developers can use &lt;em&gt;Let’s Encrypt&lt;/em&gt; to obtain a free SSL/TLS certificate for their websites and applications. This allows them to enable a secure connection for their users via HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Privacy Shield: Know the ropes before pulling data back across the pond</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/privacy-shield-know-the-ropes-before-pulling-data-back-across-the-pond"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/privacy-shield-know-the-ropes-before-pulling-data-back-across-the-pond</id>
    <published>2017-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If your U.S. company plans to bring health data from the European Union back to the states, you must address EU-U.S. Privacy Shield — an additional privacy requirement laid out by the European Court of Justice.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If your U.S. company plans to bring health data from the European Union back to the states, you must address an additional privacy requirement laid out by the European Court of Justice. The &lt;a href="https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome"&gt;EU-U.S. Privacy Shield&lt;/a&gt;, which replaced the previous Safe Harbour Framework, levies a stronger obligation on U.S. companies today. To comply, companies must either self-certify for the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield or obtain a third-party assessment. This &lt;a href="https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Join-Privacy-Shield-part-1"&gt;self-certification&lt;/a&gt; or assessment confirms that your company meets the Privacy Shield Framework requirements that help protect the personal data of Europeans.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AWS Fargate and HIPAA Compliant Containers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/aws-fargate-and-hipaa-compliant-containers"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/aws-fargate-and-hipaa-compliant-containers</id>
    <published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Rich</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Day 3 of re:Invent kicked off with AWS CEO, Andy Jassy, announcing Fargate among a slew of new AWS services. Can you tell we’re excited about Fargate?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The third day of AWS re:Invent was kicked off this morning with Andy Jassy, CEO of Amazon Web Services, announcing a slew of &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/new/reinvent/"&gt;new AWS services&lt;/a&gt;. One such service that has us excited is Fargate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>re:Invent Day #2 — Looking toward the future</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/re-invent-day-2-looking-toward-the-future"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/re-invent-day-2-looking-toward-the-future</id>
    <published>2017-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Rich</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s the second day of AWS re:Invent and sessions are in full swing. I was able to attend several healthcare track sessions yesterday (including Datica’s) and the future looks bright. Healthcare is poised to fully embrace the cloud in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s the second day of &lt;a href="https://reinvent.awsevents.com/"&gt;AWS re:Invent&lt;/a&gt; and sessions are in full swing. I was able to attend several healthcare track sessions yesterday (&lt;a href="https://datica.com/blog/how-a-major-health-system-got-onto-aws-recapping-the-featured-session-today/" title="Datica's AWS presentation"&gt;including Datica’s&lt;/a&gt;) and the future looks bright. Healthcare is poised to fully embrace the cloud in 2018. The sentiment in the market has changed and it truly feels like we’re on the edge of a major shift in the approach healthcare organizations are taking when building and hosting their software.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
