<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Datica Company Blog</title>
  <id>https://datica.com/blog/</id>
  <subtitle>Thoughts from the team behind Healthcare's trusted cloud</subtitle>
  <link href="https://datica.com/blog/" rel="self"/>
  <author>
    <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
  </author>
  <icon>https://datica.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://images.contentful.com/189dvqdsjh46/4SwayIJ5AcCe4iCU820mQs/504b8e57eacc0d81032d01ace96bc622/datica_logo__black.png?w=150</logo>
  <updated>2018-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Overview of the Current Administration's Approach to HIT</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/overview-of-current-administrations-approach-to-hit"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/overview-of-current-administrations-approach-to-hit</id>
    <published>2018-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two recent talks have shed light on what people in the healthcare information technology sector might expect from the current administration. Together, it’s clear that the administration wants to give consumers access to their health data. But, how?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Two recent talks have shed light on what people in the healthcare information technology sector might expect from the current administration. The first was a speech by Alex Azar at the Federation of American Hospitals recent meeting about value-based care, and the second, given by Seema Verna at HIMSS18, emphasized the need for interoperability among EHRs. Together, these talks make it clear that the current administration wants to give consumers access to their health data. But, how will this happen?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Payors Have Much to Gain from Advances in Technology</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/payors-gain-from-advances-in-technology"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/payors-gain-from-advances-in-technology</id>
    <published>2018-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many healthcare networks, hospitals, and physicians’ offices know they need to make improvements in order to see the greatest gains from advances in technology, and according to a recent report by the credit rating agency AM Best, insurers are in the same boat.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Many healthcare networks, hospitals, and physicians’ offices know they need to make improvements in order to see the greatest gains from advances in technology, and according to a recent report by the credit rating agency AM Best, insurers are in the same boat.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mapping Digital Health: An Interview with Dr. Ethan Bechtel, Co-Founder and CEO of OhMD</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/mapping-digital-health-dr-ethan-bechtel-ohmd"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/mapping-digital-health-dr-ethan-bechtel-ohmd</id>
    <published>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we continue our Mapping Digital Health interview series, we chatted with Dr. Ethan Bechtel, Co-Founder and CEO of OhMD about the hurdles and maturity of the digital health industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we continue our &lt;a href="https://datica.com/blog/mapping-digital-health-an-interview-with-john-moore-ceo-and-founder-twine/"&gt;Mapping Digital Health interview series&lt;/a&gt;, we chatted with Dr. Ethan Bechtel, Co-Founder and CEO of &lt;a href="http://www.ohmd.com/"&gt;OhMD&lt;/a&gt; about the hurdles and maturity of the digital health industry.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>PHI Exposed for 18 Months during UVA Data Breach</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/phi-exposed18-months-uva-data-breach"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/phi-exposed18-months-uva-data-breach</id>
    <published>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A recent data breach at the University of Virginia Health System exposed PHI for 18 months! We explore the facts and how this could have been prevented.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Often, the public learns about breaches of personal health information (PHI) because of the number of people affected. In fact organizations are required to &lt;a href="https://www.hhs.gov/hipaa/for-professionals/breach-notification/index.html"&gt;inform the media of breaches&lt;/a&gt; that affect 500 or more people, so the number of people involved is a critical component of data breach reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, a recent data breach at the University of Virginia Health System is interesting for a different reason: the length of time that PHI was exposed. The breach was discovered on December 23, 2016, and reported appropriately. The hacker had first gained access to the system, and the information of 1,882 patients’ records, on May 23, 2015, meaning the PHI was exposed for 18 months.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Microsoft and Datica Digital Health Bootcamp at SXSW</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/microsoft-datica-digital-health-bootcamp-at-sxsw"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/microsoft-datica-digital-health-bootcamp-at-sxsw</id>
    <published>2018-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kris Gösser</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Sunday March 11, we are hosting a day-long boot camp for digital health enthusiasts and entrepreneurs at South by Southwest (SXSW) in collaboration with Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This coming Sunday, March 11, we are holding a day-long boot camp for digital health enthusiasts and entrepreneurs at South by Southwest (SXSW).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is co-hosting with us. We are very excited for the opportunity to share insight on what makes digital health succeed with our friends at Microsoft who have an excellent set of speakers lined up with us.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2018 Healthcare Trends Part 5: The Real Cloud Comes to Healthcare</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/2018-trends-pt-5-real-cloud-comes-to-healthcare"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/2018-trends-pt-5-real-cloud-comes-to-healthcare</id>
    <published>2018-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Travis Good, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The “real cloud” in healthcare is not virtualization. We are talking about the public cloud and the public cloud providers Amazon, Microsoft, and Google.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Information technology groups at healthcare organizations spend a &lt;a href="https://www.beckershospitalreview.com/healthcare-information-technology/electronic-health-records-the-good-the-bad-and-the-ugly.html"&gt;colossal chunk&lt;/a&gt; of their time supporting and “optimizing” EHRs. And, with many of the largest EHR vendors, health system IT does it in-house using their own data centers. In addition to EHRs, hospital IT also has hundreds of smaller, often less essential technologies, that require care and feeding. Couple that with the needs to integrate applications and you quickly see why healthcare IT has such a huge backlog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, a significant strategic priority for healthcare organizations is assessing the cloud, developing a cloud strategy, and implementing that strategy. Most organizations are at some stage in this process. Many are still pre-implementation of a cloud strategy. But, it’s coming. And the health IT backlog is not conducive to the massive amount of work required to start moving technology to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>2018 Healthcare Trends Part 4: Clinicians as Developers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/2018-healthcare-trends-part-4-clinicians-as-developers"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/2018-healthcare-trends-part-4-clinicians-as-developers</id>
    <published>2018-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-03-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Travis Good, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In this fourth part of our 2018 Healthcare Trends series, Travis Good, MD explores what we can expect to see as clinicians broaden their skillsets into digital health.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Clinicians, in particular physicians, have always played a significant role in healthcare. Some call it an outsized role with an outsized voice; but, the last 20 years have seen a significant decline in physician autonomy as payors have stepped in to more closely oversee and dictate, via reimbursements, how clinicians practice and provide care while more and more health system has employed physicians and taken them out of independent practices. These are just the trends. There are market forces creating and sustaining these trends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this fourth part of our &lt;a href="https://datica.com/blog/6-healthcare-trends-to-watch-in-2018/"&gt;2018 Healthcare Trends&lt;/a&gt; series, I explore what we can expect to see as clinicians broaden their skillsets into digital health.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Good Guide to Surviving HIMSS 2018</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/good-guide-surviving-himss"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/good-guide-surviving-himss</id>
    <published>2018-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Travis Good, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Travis Good, MD, Co-founder, CEO &amp;amp; Chief Privacy Officer of Datica and 9-time HIMSS attendee shares his advice to surviving and staying sane at HIMSS18.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;HIMSS is my most exhausting week of the year. I think this is my 9th HIMSS. Today, with 40,000+ attendees, it’s a logistical nightmare from start to finish. Everything from transportation to coffee is a challenge. Events go late into the night, and I always seem to have an early coffee or breakfast meeting, so sleep isn’t plentiful. I’m not sure if I prefer Las Vegas to Orlando as the location for HIMSS. Both have pros and cons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is my personal HIMSS survival guide. Hopefully, I can remember these things and keep my sanity next week.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>HITRUST on AWS is possible! Find out how at HIMSS18</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/hitrust-on-aws-is-possible-find-out-how-at-himss18"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/hitrust-on-aws-is-possible-find-out-how-at-himss18</id>
    <published>2018-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kris Gösser</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;HIMSS is only a week away! On Tuesday, March 6th, Datica is presenting on the topic of HITRUST in the AWS booth #1625 at 11:00am.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;HIMSS is only a week away! On Tuesday, March 6th, Datica is presenting on the topic of HITRUST in the AWS booth #1625.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AWS asked us to share our knowledge of HITRUST with their customers, or those organizations interested in being AWS customers, in a special 20-minute session held at 11:00 am. We are excited for the opportunity to break down the fundamentals of HITRUST on AWS, and then give advice to attendees on their own journey towards HITRUST certification.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The FDA Digital Health PreCertification Program</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/fda-digital-health-precertification-program"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/fda-digital-health-precertification-program</id>
    <published>2018-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The FDA has announced a new program for digital health software developers as part of a larger effort to develop a new regulatory framework. Should you care?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The US Food and Drug Administration (FDA) has announced a new program for digital health software developers as part of a larger effort to develop a new regulatory framework. For any company that designs and develops software that is considered a medical device, this is important news.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
