<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Datica Company Blog</title>
  <id>https://datica.com/blog/</id>
  <subtitle>Thoughts from the team behind Healthcare's trusted cloud</subtitle>
  <link href="https://datica.com/blog/" rel="self"/>
  <author>
    <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
  </author>
  <icon>https://datica.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://images.contentful.com/189dvqdsjh46/4SwayIJ5AcCe4iCU820mQs/504b8e57eacc0d81032d01ace96bc622/datica_logo__black.png?w=150</logo>
  <updated>2017-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Announcing one-click installations of Mirth Connect and Open-Source Connectors</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/announcing-one-click-installations-of-mirth-connect-and-open-source"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/announcing-one-click-installations-of-mirth-connect-and-open-source</id>
    <published>2017-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mark Olschesky</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we are launching one-click installations of Mirth Connect combined with Open-Source Connectors for the Datica Platform.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today we are launching one-click installations of &lt;a href="https://www.mirth.com/"&gt;Mirth Connect&lt;/a&gt; combined with Open-Source Connectors. It is the next evolution of how we help solve the problem of healthcare data integration. The switch to a more open solution is a testament to our enduring commitment to helping customers with integration in the best way possible.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What makes HITRUST? Understanding the superset nature of HITRUST</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/what-makes-hitrust-understanding-the-superset-nature-of-hitrust"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/what-makes-hitrust-understanding-the-superset-nature-of-hitrust</id>
    <published>2017-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kris Gösser</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;HITRUST is a superset security framework and understanding both the advantages and disadvantages of this will help you wield HITRUST successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;One big reason HITRUST is taken so seriously is how it is composed of a long list of other security and risk management frameworks. HITRUST is a superset security framework and understanding both the advantages and disadvantages of this point goes a long way in understanding how to wield HITRUST successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Digital Health Success Framework: Building a Body of Evidence to Support Your Strategy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/dhsf-building-a-body-of-evidence-to-support-your-strategy-roadmap"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/dhsf-building-a-body-of-evidence-to-support-your-strategy-roadmap</id>
    <published>2017-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The latest addition to the DHSF is meant to help you gain a better understanding of the evidence needed for your digital health strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s so much for makers of digital health products to plan for as part of their digital health strategy. At Datica, one of the main things we do is to strive to simplify the complex world of digital health, making it easier for developers of new products to succeed. It is this goal that drove us to produce the &lt;a href="https://datica.com/dhsf/"&gt;Digital Health Success Framework&lt;/a&gt; — a living document that provides a guide through the journey of developing a HIPAA compliant application for healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By saying this is a live document, what I mean is that we are continually adding to it and improving it to increase its relevancy. Our latest addition to the DHSF is a new section meant to help you gain a better understanding of the evidence needed as part of your digital health strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Esther Dyson Q&amp;A: On digital health and getting to the end game</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/esther-dyson-q-and-a-on-digital-health-and-getting-to-the-end-game"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/esther-dyson-q-and-a-on-digital-health-and-getting-to-the-end-game</id>
    <published>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Esther Dyson, whose career includes journalist, author, businesswoman, commentator, philanthropist, angel investor, and even backup cosmonaut, sat down for an interview with Datica CEO Travis Good, MD.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This November, the &lt;a href="https://datica.com/podcast/"&gt;Healthcare Innovators Podcast&lt;/a&gt; interviewed a very special industry guest. Due to audio difficulties, we chose to run a transcript of our fascinating conversation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esther Dyson has worn many different hats during the course of her career, including journalist, author, businesswoman, commentator, philanthropist, angel investor, and yes, even backup cosmonaut. Esther sat down for an interview with Datica CEO Travis Good, MD. In this interview, she shared some of her thoughts around ways to increase digital health success, the importance of security and privacy for digital health firms, and gave us an update on her nonprofit initiative that selected five American communities to use different measures to cultivate health and invest in the value wellness returns.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Health 2.0 Lunch &amp; Learn Recap: What does the success of digital health look like?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/health-2-0-lunch-and-learn-recap-what-digital-health-success-look-like"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/health-2-0-lunch-and-learn-recap-what-digital-health-success-look-like</id>
    <published>2017-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At Health 2.0 2017, a panel of leaders who have worked in the trenches discussed the most important
factors for the success of digital health products.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recent news tells us that digital health startups drew record investments in the first half of 2017. Sadly, according to research by Accenture, more than half of those digital health startups are likely to fail within two years following launch. How do digital health teams launch products that succeed?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Do you Have $360K to Build Compliance into your Digital Health Product Yourself?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/do-you-have-360k-to-build-compliance-into-your-digital-health-product"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/do-you-have-360k-to-build-compliance-into-your-digital-health-product</id>
    <published>2017-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;$360,000! The cost for a maker of digital health products to design, implement, deploy and prove HIPAA compliance all on their own. Get the breakdown.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;$360,000! That’s how much it will cost a typical maker of digital health products to design, implement, deploy, and prove HIPAA compliance all on their own. That cost doesn’t even include their basic cloud subscription or the cost of developing the technology for their own application. We often hear early-stage developers say they’ve got compliance covered since they’re using AWS. That’s when the steep education process begins to help them understand they’re just at the beginning of the compliance journey with AWS and there’s so much more to consider to build a compliant application in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Using GNU Privacy Guard and OpenPGP to Automatically Decrypt SFTP Files</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/using-gnu-privacy-guard-and-openpgp-to-automatically-decrypt-sftp-files"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/using-gnu-privacy-guard-and-openpgp-to-automatically-decrypt-sftp-files</id>
    <published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Richards</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The GnuPG is a free implementation of OpenPGP — the most widely used email encryption standard. Learn how to use GnuPG and OpenPG to automatically decrypt encrypted SFTP files.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="why-is-encryption-important"&gt;Why is encryption important?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HIPAA compliance has requirements for the transfer and storage of &lt;a href="https://datica.com/academy/what-is-protected-health-information-or-phi/"&gt;Protected Health Information (PHI)&lt;/a&gt;. Standard SSH file transfer can securely transfer data onto the &lt;a href="https://datica.com/platform/"&gt;Datica Platform&lt;/a&gt;. However, the files need to be encrypted at rest on the SSH sender’s storage volume before being doubly encrypted/decrypted during the SSH transfer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you can manage part of your encryption for transfer yourself, you still need to have a method for encrypting storage volumes, containers, and the data transferred between those services. Datica’s platform meets those requirements for everything, once the data makes it onto the platform (HITRUST-audited policy 17.9).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mapping Digital Health: An interview with Strata Health Executive VP Peter Smith</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/mapping-digital-health-interview-with-strata-health-vp-peter-smith"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/mapping-digital-health-interview-with-strata-health-vp-peter-smith</id>
    <published>2017-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This second interview of our “Mapping the Digital Health Landscape” series, highlights innovation at Strata Health in the U.S. and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This second interview of our “Mapping the Digital Health Landscape” series, highlights the digital health innovation of Strata Health within the United States, and beyond. Operational in North America, the UK, France, and Australia, Strata Health is a privately held Canadian corporation of professionals with empathy for those who need care and intense respect for those who devote themselves to caring for others.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Will new identity-proofing NIST standards prove who you say you are?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/will-new-identity-proofing-nist-standards-prove-who-you-say-you-are"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/will-new-identity-proofing-nist-standards-prove-who-you-say-you-are</id>
    <published>2017-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A recent NIST update includes important changes that encourage out of band authentication methods versus a single source email. Learn how Datica is responding.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity risk management has quickly moved from the “nagging mosquito” kind of problem that every industry must swat to one more likened to a full frontal attack, requiring more arsenal than budgets sometimes allow. Everywhere, from White House hacks into communication emails to security breaches, like the recent one announced by Equifax that has affected 145.5 million Americans, leave cybercriminals more in touch with our private financial and healthcare data than perhaps we are ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Public vs. Private Cloud Computing Examined: Our Latest Quarterly Industry Report</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/public-vs-private-cloud-computing-examined-our-latest-quarterly-industry"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/public-vs-private-cloud-computing-examined-our-latest-quarterly-industry</id>
    <published>2017-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kris Gösser</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our latest industry report takes a look at various opinions and definitions on public vs. private cloud computing within healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last quarter, we published our first industry report titled &lt;a href="https://datica.com/innovation/heart-of-medicine-report-spring-2017/"&gt;The Heart of Medicine: Transformation Through Technology&lt;/a&gt;. The report took a look at how sentiments have changed the last few years around the topic of “cloud” within enterprise healthcare. Measuring the changes between a 2014 HIMSS study and their 2017 version showed that certain use cases on the cloud have not just taken off, but are commonplace—a good sign for the progress of digital health.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
