<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Datica Company Blog</title>
  <id>https://datica.com/blog/</id>
  <subtitle>Thoughts from the team behind Healthcare's trusted cloud</subtitle>
  <link href="https://datica.com/blog/" rel="self"/>
  <author>
    <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
  </author>
  <icon>https://datica.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://images.contentful.com/189dvqdsjh46/4SwayIJ5AcCe4iCU820mQs/504b8e57eacc0d81032d01ace96bc622/datica_logo__black.png?w=150</logo>
  <updated>2018-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>10 Most-Read Articles of 2017</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/10-most-read-articles-of-2017"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/10-most-read-articles-of-2017</id>
    <published>2018-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2018-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What was healthcare reading to stay on top of their technology game in 2017? Our top 10 blogs show cloud and compliance as top of mind for many of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What were healthcare developers and leaders reading to stay on top of their technology game in 2017? If the following list of top articles from the Datica blog is any indication, cloud and compliance were top of mind for many of you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Q4 Industry Report: Shadow IT's positives and negatives within healthcare</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/q4-industry-report-shadow-its-positives-and-negatives-within-healthcare"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/q4-industry-report-shadow-its-positives-and-negatives-within-healthcare</id>
    <published>2017-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kris Gösser</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Datica’s Winter 2017 quarterly industry report examines the paradox of shadow IT in healthcare. Is it a security threat or enabler for innovation?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://datica.com/innovation/shadow-it-in-healthcare-cloud-cover-for-innovation-initiatives"&gt;The Winter installment of Datica’s quarterly industry report is now available&lt;/a&gt;. The report examines shadow IT as both a growing security threat to health IT, but also as a unique and unrivaled enabler for innovation when managed appropriately. Shadow IT as a topic is quite the paradox—this report tries to help make sense of it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How does GDPR compare to HIPAA?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/how-does-gdpr-compare-to-hipaa"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/how-does-gdpr-compare-to-hipaa</id>
    <published>2017-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Travis Good, MD</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Though different in who they apply to and how you prove compliance, HIPAA and GDPR are both about having security as a core tenet of operations.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At the AWS re:Invent conference earlier this month, GDPR was a major area of interest from attendees though AWS has little content coverage for GDPR. GDPR, which stands for General Data Protection Regulation, is the acronym for the much anticipated new EU security and privacy framework that goes into effect in May of 2018. GDPR leaves some discretion to EU member states but, as a general rule, and the reason it is getting so much attention, is that it applies across all EU Member States. The purpose of this post is to introduce those familiar with healthcare privacy and security in the United States, namely those concerned with HIPAA, to GDPR. This post doesn’t get into technical requirements, or even security requirements more generally, but instead focuses on the broader principles and privacy guidelines for health data under GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why Let's Encrypt is our favorite open source project this year</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/why-lets-encrypt-is-our-favorite-open-source-project-this-year"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/why-lets-encrypt-is-our-favorite-open-source-project-this-year</id>
    <published>2017-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Rich</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This holiday season, we’re proud to support one of our favorite open source projects, Let’s Encrypt, in their mission to make the internet more secure.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We highly value open-source technology at Datica. We’re not only contributors to the open source community, but &lt;a href="https://datica.com/blog/announcing-one-click-installations-of-mirth-connect-and-open-source/"&gt;open source users&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://datica.com/open-source/"&gt;producers&lt;/a&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One such open source project that we’re absolutely thrilled to be using is &lt;a href="https://letsencrypt.org/"&gt;Let’s Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Let’s Encrypt&lt;/em&gt; is a completely free and open source certificate authority. Developers can use &lt;em&gt;Let’s Encrypt&lt;/em&gt; to obtain a free SSL/TLS certificate for their websites and applications. This allows them to enable a secure connection for their users via HTTPS.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Privacy Shield: Know the ropes before pulling data back across the pond</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/privacy-shield-know-the-ropes-before-pulling-data-back-across-the-pond"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/privacy-shield-know-the-ropes-before-pulling-data-back-across-the-pond</id>
    <published>2017-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-12-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;If your U.S. company plans to bring health data from the European Union back to the states, you must address EU-U.S. Privacy Shield — an additional privacy requirement laid out by the European Court of Justice.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If your U.S. company plans to bring health data from the European Union back to the states, you must address an additional privacy requirement laid out by the European Court of Justice. The &lt;a href="https://www.privacyshield.gov/welcome"&gt;EU-U.S. Privacy Shield&lt;/a&gt;, which replaced the previous Safe Harbour Framework, levies a stronger obligation on U.S. companies today. To comply, companies must either self-certify for the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield or obtain a third-party assessment. This &lt;a href="https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Join-Privacy-Shield-part-1"&gt;self-certification&lt;/a&gt; or assessment confirms that your company meets the Privacy Shield Framework requirements that help protect the personal data of Europeans.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>AWS Fargate and HIPAA Compliant Containers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/aws-fargate-and-hipaa-compliant-containers"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/aws-fargate-and-hipaa-compliant-containers</id>
    <published>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Rich</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Day 3 of re:Invent kicked off with AWS CEO, Andy Jassy, announcing Fargate among a slew of new AWS services. Can you tell we’re excited about Fargate?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The third day of AWS re:Invent was kicked off this morning with Andy Jassy, CEO of Amazon Web Services, announcing a slew of &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/new/reinvent/"&gt;new AWS services&lt;/a&gt;. One such service that has us excited is Fargate.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>re:Invent Day #2 — Looking toward the future</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/re-invent-day-2-looking-toward-the-future"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/re-invent-day-2-looking-toward-the-future</id>
    <published>2017-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Ryan Rich</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s the second day of AWS re:Invent and sessions are in full swing. I was able to attend several healthcare track sessions yesterday (including Datica’s) and the future looks bright. Healthcare is poised to fully embrace the cloud in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It’s the second day of &lt;a href="https://reinvent.awsevents.com/"&gt;AWS re:Invent&lt;/a&gt; and sessions are in full swing. I was able to attend several healthcare track sessions yesterday (&lt;a href="https://datica.com/blog/how-a-major-health-system-got-onto-aws-recapping-the-featured-session-today/" title="Datica's AWS presentation"&gt;including Datica’s&lt;/a&gt;) and the future looks bright. Healthcare is poised to fully embrace the cloud in 2018. The sentiment in the market has changed and it truly feels like we’re on the edge of a major shift in the approach healthcare organizations are taking when building and hosting their software.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>How a major Health System got onto AWS: Recapping the featured session today at AWS re:Invent</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/how-a-major-health-system-got-onto-aws-recapping-the-featured-session-today"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/how-a-major-health-system-got-onto-aws-recapping-the-featured-session-today</id>
    <published>2017-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kris Gösser</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Adam Leko and David Deas discussed how the Datica Platform helped Memphis Le Bonheur (MLH) health system get onto AWS through removing the burden of DevOps and security in a HITRUST CSF Certified way.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;David Deas and Memphis Le Bonheur (MLH) have a mandate to improve patient care, improve the lives of clinicians, and save the organization money in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a 20+ year veteran of healthcare and a computer scientist by trade, David knows a thing or two about how to get work done within the confines of healthcare’s regulations or internal IT politics. He was the leader in implementing Cerner at MLH in the 90s. Now, in his role as head of innovation at MLH, he’s charged with faster-paced objectives where speed-to-market is imperative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internal IT has been less than helpful. On stage today, David spoke about the “Ticket Hell” he has to go through to provision any technical resources for his team.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The AWS re:Invent Ultimate Guide for Makers of Digital Health Products</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/aws-reinvent-ultimate-guide-for-makers-of-digital-health-products"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/aws-reinvent-ultimate-guide-for-makers-of-digital-health-products</id>
    <published>2017-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With 1,000 sessions to choose from, we offer a bit of help to our friends out there in the healthcare industry who might be attending AWS re:Invent next week.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With more than a thousand possible sessions to choose from and so many parties to attend, we thought we’d offer a bit of help to our friends out there in the healthcare industry who might be attending &lt;em&gt;AWS re:Invent&lt;/em&gt; next week. In addition to presenting and exhibiting, many of our own people will be at the following sessions, chalk talks, panel discussions, and, of course, at the healthcare happy hour. Don’t forget to stop by the Datica booth #519 while you’re there. See you next week!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the entire session list &lt;a href="https://www.portal.reinvent.awsevents.com/connect/search.ww"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mapping Digital Health: An interview with John Moore, CEO and Founder Twine Health</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/mapping-digital-health-an-interview-with-john-moore-ceo-and-founder-twine"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/mapping-digital-health-an-interview-with-john-moore-ceo-and-founder-twine</id>
    <published>2017-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;What does a breakdancing eye surgeon have to say about patient engagement? Find out in the 3rd issue of “Mapping Digital Health” with Dr. John Moore of Twine Health.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What does a breakdancing eye surgeon have to say about healthcare today? As the third in our &lt;a href="/blog/mapping-digital-health-an-interview-with-c-sats-co-founder-derek-streat/"&gt;Mapping Digital Health&lt;/a&gt; series of interviews, we asked &lt;a href="https://www.twinehealth.com/john-moore"&gt;Dr. John Moore&lt;/a&gt;, CEO and Founder of Twine Health, about the status of patient engagement in healthcare. Moore’s entrepreneurial career had an unusual start when, as an undergrad at Boston University, he founded a breakdancing club. As he completed medical school and trained to become a specialized eye surgeon, he recognized a major break in communication between patients and their doctors once they left their doctor’s offices. Moore founded &lt;a href="https://www.twinehealth.com"&gt;Twine Health&lt;/a&gt; in order to create technology that really reaches patients.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
