<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Datica Company Blog</title>
  <id>https://datica.com/blog/</id>
  <subtitle>Thoughts from the team behind Healthcare's trusted cloud</subtitle>
  <link href="https://datica.com/blog/" rel="self"/>
  <author>
    <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
  </author>
  <icon>https://datica.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://images.contentful.com/189dvqdsjh46/4SwayIJ5AcCe4iCU820mQs/504b8e57eacc0d81032d01ace96bc622/datica_logo__black.png?w=150</logo>
  <updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Using GNU Privacy Guard and OpenPGP to Automatically Decrypt SFTP Files</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/using-gnu-privacy-guard-and-openpgp-to-automatically-decrypt-sftp-files"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/using-gnu-privacy-guard-and-openpgp-to-automatically-decrypt-sftp-files</id>
    <published>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Eric Richards</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The GnuPG is a free implementation of OpenPGP — the most widely used email encryption standard. Learn how to use GnuPG and OpenPG to automatically decrypt encrypted SFTP files.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id="why-is-encryption-important"&gt;Why is encryption important?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HIPAA compliance has requirements for the transfer and storage of &lt;a href="https://datica.com/academy/what-is-protected-health-information-or-phi/"&gt;Protected Health Information (PHI)&lt;/a&gt;. Standard SSH file transfer can securely transfer data onto the &lt;a href="https://datica.com/platform/"&gt;Datica Platform&lt;/a&gt;. However, the files need to be encrypted at rest on the SSH sender’s storage volume before being doubly encrypted/decrypted during the SSH transfer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you can manage part of your encryption for transfer yourself, you still need to have a method for encrypting storage volumes, containers, and the data transferred between those services. Datica’s platform meets those requirements for everything, once the data makes it onto the platform (HITRUST-audited policy 17.9).&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mapping Digital Health: An interview with Strata Health Executive VP Peter Smith</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/mapping-digital-health-interview-with-strata-health-vp-peter-smith"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/mapping-digital-health-interview-with-strata-health-vp-peter-smith</id>
    <published>2017-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This second interview of our “Mapping the Digital Health Landscape” series, highlights innovation at Strata Health in the U.S. and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This second interview of our “Mapping the Digital Health Landscape” series, highlights the digital health innovation of Strata Health within the United States, and beyond. Operational in North America, the UK, France, and Australia, Strata Health is a privately held Canadian corporation of professionals with empathy for those who need care and intense respect for those who devote themselves to caring for others.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Will new identity-proofing NIST standards prove who you say you are?</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/will-new-identity-proofing-nist-standards-prove-who-you-say-you-are"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/will-new-identity-proofing-nist-standards-prove-who-you-say-you-are</id>
    <published>2017-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A recent NIST update includes important changes that encourage out of band authentication methods versus a single source email. Learn how Datica is responding.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Cybersecurity risk management has quickly moved from the “nagging mosquito” kind of problem that every industry must swat to one more likened to a full frontal attack, requiring more arsenal than budgets sometimes allow. Everywhere, from White House hacks into communication emails to security breaches, like the recent one announced by Equifax that has affected 145.5 million Americans, leave cybercriminals more in touch with our private financial and healthcare data than perhaps we are ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Public vs. Private Cloud Computing Examined: Our Latest Quarterly Industry Report</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/public-vs-private-cloud-computing-examined-our-latest-quarterly-industry"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/public-vs-private-cloud-computing-examined-our-latest-quarterly-industry</id>
    <published>2017-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kris Gösser</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Our latest industry report takes a look at various opinions and definitions on public vs. private cloud computing within healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last quarter, we published our first industry report titled &lt;a href="https://datica.com/innovation/heart-of-medicine-report-spring-2017/"&gt;The Heart of Medicine: Transformation Through Technology&lt;/a&gt;. The report took a look at how sentiments have changed the last few years around the topic of “cloud” within enterprise healthcare. Measuring the changes between a 2014 HIMSS study and their 2017 version showed that certain use cases on the cloud have not just taken off, but are commonplace—a good sign for the progress of digital health.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Looking in the Rearview Mirror at Health 2.0, 2012</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/looking-in-the-rearview-mirror-at-health-2-0-2012"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/looking-in-the-rearview-mirror-at-health-2-0-2012</id>
    <published>2017-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mark Olschesky</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Where do the many predictions and technologies from Health 2.0, 2012 stand today? Which products were a hit? What predictions came to be true—or didn’t?&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;As we get our booth shipped and bags packed for Health 2.0 this year, I started thinking about when I first attended Health 2.0 five years ago. It was held at the Hilton in Union Square in San Francisco. I was in town for my startup’s interview at Rock Health, which at the time was just a stroll down Geary and a left on Grant through the &lt;a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:San_Francisco_Dragon_Gate_to_Chinatown.jpg"&gt;Dragon Gate&lt;/a&gt; to the Rock Health offices in Chinatown. It was my first day ever in San Francisco; a place I would soon call home as I spent a chunk of 2012-2013 in the city for Rock Health.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Mapping Digital Health: An interview with C-SATS co-founder Derek Streat</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/mapping-digital-health-an-interview-with-c-sats-co-founder-derek-streat"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/mapping-digital-health-an-interview-with-c-sats-co-founder-derek-streat</id>
    <published>2017-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kris Gösser</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Datica is excited every day about the emerging digital health landscape. We know there are many other entrepreneurs who, like us, use technology to help healthcare organizations better serve their patients. That is why we created an ongoing series called “Mapping the Digital Health Landscape,” highlighting the great work pursued by fellow digital health innovators.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Datica is excited every day about the emerging digital health landscape. We know there are many other entrepreneurs who, like us, use technology to help healthcare organizations better serve their patients. That is why we have created the ongoing series called “Mapping the Digital Health Landscape,” highlighting the great work pursued by fellow digital health innovators.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Webinar: What is the Digital Health Success Framework? </title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/webinar-what-is-the-digital-health-success-framework"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/webinar-what-is-the-digital-health-success-framework</id>
    <published>2017-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Kris Gösser</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Mark Olschesky will summarize the origins and utility of the Digital Health Success Framework in an upcoming webinar scheduled for Sept. 25th, at 12pm CST.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;When we launched the &lt;a href="https://datica.com/dhsf"&gt;Digital Health Success Framework&lt;/a&gt; (DHSF) this summer, the immediate reaction from the health IT community, and from digital health teams specifically, was immensely positive. It was like getting a high 5 from a stranger every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since launch, we learned its greatest strength is also its greatest current weakness. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>HITRUST CSF Certification Round 3</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/hitrust-csf-certification-round-3"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/hitrust-csf-certification-round-3</id>
    <published>2017-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Laleh Hassibi</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With our 3rd HITRUST CSF certification, the Datica Platform now provides customers greater flexibility with cloud infrastructure choices.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;HIPAA regulations create a barrier for makers of digital health products to adopt the cloud. Whether you are a digital health startup, a health system, payer, or life sciences organization, it takes an enormous amount of work to &lt;a href="https://datica.com/dhsf/"&gt;get your digital health product off the ground&lt;/a&gt; while, at the same time, achieving and maintaining continuous HIPAA compliance.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Lifting A Fork for Open Source</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/lifting-a-fork-for-open-source"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/lifting-a-fork-for-open-source</id>
    <published>2017-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This Q&amp;amp;A with Datica’s Chief Data Officer, Mark Olschesky, explores what it means that Datica just passed 200 forks of our open-source policies.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A week ago, Chief Data Officer &lt;a href="https://datica.com/about/mark/"&gt;Mark Olschesky&lt;/a&gt; used Slack to announce that Datica had just passed 200 forks of our open-source policies. Of course, the company wise-crackers quickly posted the obligatory Yogi Berra response:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When you come to a fork in the road, take it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>If It's Possible, We Can Integrate It</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/blog/if-its-possible-we-can-integrate-it"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/blog/if-its-possible-we-can-integrate-it</id>
    <published>2017-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Mark Olschesky</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;There’s much a digital health company needs to know about EHR integrations. Here are 4 essential questions digital health teams should ask their customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;During the past three years, we’ve done &lt;a href="https://datica.com/platform/success/"&gt;a lot of integration work&lt;/a&gt;. We’ve worked on more than 150 integration projects with almost 30 EHR vendors. We’ve done this work with big organizations and vendors to small FQHCs and niche EHR vendors. As a result of all this integration experience, we now have a pretty good grasp on the intricacies of how integration works. We can reasonably estimate how long it takes us to do a project and how that varies with different types of vendors.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
