<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Datica Health Press Releases</title>
  <id>https://datica.com/press/</id>
  <subtitle>Thoughts from the team behind Healthcare's trusted cloud</subtitle>
  <link href="https://datica.com/press-release/" rel="self"/>
  <author>
    <name>Datica Health, Inc.</name>
  </author>
  <icon>https://datica.com/favicon.ico</icon>
  <logo>https://images.contentful.com/189dvqdsjh46/4SwayIJ5AcCe4iCU820mQs/504b8e57eacc0d81032d01ace96bc622/datica_logo__black.png?w=150</logo>
  <updated>2017-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica to Host Panel Discussing Digital Health Success at Health 2.0</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press-release/datica-to-host-panel-discussing-digital-health-success-at-health-2-0"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press-release/datica-to-host-panel-discussing-digital-health-success-at-health-2-0</id>
    <published>2017-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Panel event to feature three prominent digital health leaders who share ideas on ways to increase chances of digital health product success.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;MADISON, WISC. (PRWEB) SEPTEMBER 28, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datica, the leading cloud platform for digital health applications, today announced a panel event at the Health 2.0 Fall Conference in Santa Clara, Calif. The annual conference, which attracts 2,000 digital health decision makers, will be held October 1 - 4 at the Santa Clara Convention Center. Datica’s digital health panel titled “What does the success of digital health look like?” will be on Monday, Oct. 1 from 12:30-1:30 pm, in Grand Ballroom E.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendees to the panel session will hear deeply held thoughts on past success and failures in digital health from three distinguished panelists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Christiana DelloRusso, Ph.D., Partner of Providence Ventures, the strategic venture capital arm of Providence St. Joseph Health.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kristi Ebong, Director Emerging Health Technology, Cedars-Sinai&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carolyn Jasik, MD, Medical Director of Omada Health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datica CEO Travis Good, MD, will moderate the informative session providing the most important observations from those who work in the digital health trenches. Attendees who want to increase chances of succeeding in the digital health space will walk away from the noonday session with solid answers to these questions and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Does the business model of a digital health product factor as the biggest reason for later failure or success?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can health systems or payers help digital health succeed?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How important are pilots to the success of a digital health product?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We are excited to sponsor Health 2.0 and bring this dynamic session to the conference. Since the company’s founding four years ago, we’ve had thousands of conversations around industry frustrations, hopes, success and failures with digital health vendors and providers,” said Travis Good, MD, Datica CEO. “Those conversations have led to the development of Datica’s &lt;a href="https://datica.com/dhsf"&gt;Digital Health Success Framework (DHSF)&lt;/a&gt;, and this panel provides the opportunity to create one of the first open forum discussions that will help aid the progress of those developing digital health products today.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the conference, digital health self-assessments will be conducted in Datica’s booth #204 on the exhibit floor. Get more information on the Digital Health Success Framework at http://www.datica.com/dhsf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="about-datica"&gt;About Datica&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datica is the platform for digital health success. We solve the problem of HIPAA compliance in the cloud, and enable secure data exchange between digital health and EHRs. Customers and partners across healthcare trust Datica to ensure the barriers for digital health are removed so innovation can happen faster. For more information please visit http://www.datica.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Releases Observations from 7 Healthcare Technology Industry Icons</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press-release/datica-releases-observations-from-7-healthcare-technology-industry-icons"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press-release/datica-releases-observations-from-7-healthcare-technology-industry-icons</id>
    <published>2017-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Datica, the leading cloud platform for digital health applications, today published its seminal Thought Leadership Gallery titled “Rethinking Health Technology” for key stakeholders in healthcare. Industry luminaries like Gregory Ator, MD; Brad Schwartz, MD; Jocelyn DeWitt, PhD; Jacob Behrens, MD, Matt Fenty, Marc Chasin, MD and Lyle Berkowitz, MD share their unique perspectives on technology’s impact on healthcare in this e-book.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;MADISON, WISC. (PRWEB) AUGUST 22, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datica, the leading cloud platform for digital health applications, today published its seminal &lt;a href="https://datica.com/innovation/leadership-gallery/"&gt;Thought Leadership Gallery&lt;/a&gt; titled “Rethinking Health Technology” for key stakeholders in healthcare. Industry luminaries like Gregory Ator, MD; Brad Schwartz, MD; Jocelyn DeWitt, PhD; Jacob Behrens, MD, Matt Fenty, Marc Chasin, MD and Lyle Berkowitz, MD share their unique perspectives on technology’s impact on healthcare in this e-book. This thought leadership collection allows readers to get a glimpse into the strong stance each of these clinicians hold on the topic of technology, including where it fits well, where it doesn’t fit and what can be done to improve the healthcare technology landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datica’s first Thought Leadership Gallery delivers powerful thoughts around questions these notable figures consider as they work in an industry on the cusp of radical transformation. Some of the questions posed include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Should the industry take a standardized approach to how it adopts and deploy new capabilities?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Will technology bring back joy to the clinician workflow?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has the industry begun aligning incentives to promote innovation?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Should the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) be changed to allow for innovation?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do clinicians feel about patients owning their own records?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is patient stratification the next frontier for improving patient outcomes?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The Thought Leadership Gallery gives a voice to physicians and clinicians who are at the heart of healthcare’s digital revolution,” said Datica CEO and Chief Privacy Officer Travis Good, MD. “With minimal input into the digital tools that are often selected, vendors don’t have a compelling reason to understand the specific needs of clinicians, and that ultimately impacts patient care. Our series of thought leadership papers will help professionals on all sides of the healthcare prism understand those clinician needs for delivering better outcomes.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download Datica’s full &lt;a href="https://datica.com/innovation/leadership-gallery/"&gt;Thought Leadership Gallery here&lt;/a&gt; to learn how influential industry thinkers and doers are assessing the impact of technology on healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Introduces the Digital Health Success Framework</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press-release/datica-introduces-the-digital-health-success-framework"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press-release/datica-introduces-the-digital-health-success-framework</id>
    <published>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Teams and organizations across healthcare can follow the industry’s first roadmap to accelerate digital health success.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;MADISON, WISC. (PRWEB) JULY 12, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datica, the industry cloud platform for digital health applications, today announced its Digital Health Success Framework (DHSF). Digital health developers can use the detailed guide to take products from napkin scribble to market without any snags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launched in 2013, Datica has spent the past four years working with digital health companies that range from single-founder startups to Fortune 100 pharma companies and hospital providers. Patterns from thousands of conversations have emerged around topics like technology, cloud infrastructure, data exchange and compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Unlike other industries where a pathway to success is straightforward, the healthcare industry has unique considerations not found elsewhere,” said Mark Olschesky, Datica’s chief data officer. “The DHSF takes those specific complexities, details the timelines and benchmarks for each, then simplifies the success process in an intelligent way that developers can clearly comprehend.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to research and data analytics firm CB Insights, increases in digital health funding continued for the seventh straight year in 2016 with venture deals reaching $6.5B. Those financial deals have financially supported companies that want to “remedy the pain points of healthcare.” Investors distributed the majority of those funds to early-stage, seed and Series A companies. Yet, Datica has seen many of those well-intentioned companies struggle to reach market adoption. Research by Accenture in 2015 showed that more than 50 percent of all digital health startups are likely to fail within two years following their launch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datica’s mission is to reduce that 50 percent rate. The Digital Health Success Framework plays the role of helping teams understand the major considerations which contribute to business risks and product burdens. “We’ve seen hundreds of digital health companies pass by in our position as a top startup incubator. Most of them struggle to understand what challenges stand between them and market adoption,” explained Joe Kirgues, co-founder of Gener8tor, a nationally ranked accelerator. “Datica’s Digital Health Success Framework can help organizations understand the unique considerations required for new products, which will help the healthcare ecosystem only get better at delivering stronger patient outcomes through new innovation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on the Digital Health Success Framework, visit &lt;a href="https://datica.com/dhsf"&gt;https://datica.com/dhsf&lt;/a&gt;. The free resource charts dozens of important considerations for digital health teams along a four-year timeline, ranging from HIPAA compliance to pilot strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id="about-datica"&gt;About Datica&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datica is the platform for digital health success. We solve the problem of HIPAA compliance in the cloud, and enable secure data exchange between digital health and EHRs. Customers and partners across healthcare trust Datica to ensure the barriers for digital health are removed so innovation can happen faster. For more information please visit http://www.datica.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Datica Names Kevin Lindbergh Chief Revenue Officer</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press-release/datica-names-kevin-lindbergh-chief-revenue-officer"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press-release/datica-names-kevin-lindbergh-chief-revenue-officer</id>
    <published>2017-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-04-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Internal hire will accelerate the industry-wide adoption of the company’s platform for digital health success and will supply additional strategic direction as the company grows.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;MADISON, WISC. (PRWEB) APRIL 26, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datica, the industry platform for digital health success, today announced Kevin Lindbergh will lead the company’s revenue generating efforts and execute on an aggressive product development strategy begun in late 2016. As the Chief Revenue Officer (CRO), Kevin will provide strategic direction for the sales, marketing, and product teams that help drive the company’s revenue streams, as well as identify new opportunities for growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“As the board and I considered filling the newly created position of CRO, the wealth of talent from within our own team enabled us to tap a valuable internal source,” said Travis Good, MD, CEO, Datica. “Kevin will be accelerating our top-line revenue with hospital systems by drawing upon the expertise of Kris Gösser, vice president of marketing and Ryan Rich, Datica’s newly appointed vice president of product. Kevin will also provide oversight on the day-today sales efforts to digital health vendors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kevin has a successful track record within Datica and was initially hired as the company’s Vice President of Sales in June 2015. With his deep expertise in healthcare, combined with a laser vision and strategy for company growth, he quickly recognized the significant potential Datica’s platform for digital health success could have on the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital healthcare is messy, but Datica’s mission to connect patients and providers with the tools and data they need to optimize care is one that won’t be solved by putting an API on top of an electronic health record. “We know that a customer who has an immediate need for compliant hosting or managed integration will eventually need other pieces like strategic services to achieve scalable success within digital health,” explained Lindbergh. “The industry has become leery of the piecemeal approach, so Datica’s full stack delivery layer empowers development teams with knowledge that their technology efforts are anchored on our unified platform; feature sets can simply be expanded as needed.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most recently, Kevin managed strategic relationships and did solution design at a startup focused on human capital management automation and enterprise collaboration. Prior to that, he held leadership positions in several healthcare organizations, including founding his own company focused on healthcare consumerism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About Datica&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datica is the platform for digital health success. We solve the problem of HIPAA compliance in the cloud, and enable secure data exchange between digital health and EHRs. Customers and partners across healthcare trust Datica to ensure the barriers for digital health are removed so innovation can happen faster. For more information please visit http://www.datica.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Catalyze Rebrands as Datica, Solidifies its Unique Mark on Healthcare</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press-release/catalyze-rebrands-as-datica-solidifies-its-unique-mark-on-healthcare"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press-release/catalyze-rebrands-as-datica-solidifies-its-unique-mark-on-healthcare</id>
    <published>2017-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2017-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Company that unlocked the problem of securely hosting healthcare data in the cloud changes its name to better reflect its core focus during an industry transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;MADISON, WIS. (PRWEB) FEBRUARY 07, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catalyze, the company that brought cloud-based HIPAA compliant hosting and managed integration services to healthcare, today announced a corporate name change to Datica. As part of the switch to &lt;a href="https://datica.com"&gt;Datica&lt;/a&gt;, the company unveiled a complete top-to-bottom redesign of its existing website and introduced a new logo to showcase the company’s fresh look. This latest public announcement falls on the heels of a multi-million dollar &lt;a href="http://www.prweb.com/releases/2016/09/prweb13694385.htm"&gt;Series B funding&lt;/a&gt; round announced last fall and two weeks prior to &lt;a href="http://www.himssconference.org/"&gt;HIMSS17&lt;/a&gt;, the largest and most important health IT conference of the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The intentional decision to rename the company was based on its success in healthcare and involved both protecting what has become a unique business platform and also a way to set vision for the future. “Within three years, our path from Catalyze to Datica involved a swift move from early startup to mature and thriving company, serving virtually all constituencies in healthcare,” explained Datica CEO Travis Good, MD. “Obtaining a unique and strong company name that reflects the full depth and breadth of current expertise, as well as our vision for the future, prompted the ‘now versus later’ decision.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A distinctive trademark allows a company to make the strongest possible impression on the marketplace. The name ‘Datica’ offers that distinction. Carlos Romero, head of Trademark &amp;amp; Technology Transactions at Adobecity World Legal Consulting in San Francisco, who helped the company legally navigate the rebrand, said the best time to address a corporate name change is early, or as soon as feasibly possible. “Trademark law tends to favor distinctive terms which are granted the broadest levels of protection under federal law. One major issue with Catalyze was the sheer number of marks in the software industry using similar wording such as ‘Catalyze’ and ‘Catalyst.’ That made it more difficult to gain and maintain protection with the US Patent and Trademark Office.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of many challenges in selecting a company name is finding one that accurately reflects the essence of the products and services a company offers. Protected health information (PHI), or essentially “data,” is at the core of everything Datica has done, first protecting health information in the cloud, then developing a method of moving, sharing, and translating data to and from electronic health records. Datica precisely mirrors that core business focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This is the perfect time for repositioning the company; healthcare is in a transformational period and as a trusted partner to the industry, we plan to be well in front of where the puck is headed, and that includes the evolution of our company brand,” said Travis Good, MD, Datica CEO&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information about the transition to Datica or to learn more about the company’s &lt;a href="/compliant-cloud"&gt;HIPAA compliant hosting&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="/managed-integration"&gt;managed integration services&lt;/a&gt;, stop by booth #8152 at HIMSS17, located near the Intelligent Health Pavilion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="about-datica"&gt;About Datica&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datica makes digital health in the cloud a reality by removing the risks that prevent its adoption. We turn HIPAA compliance on public infrastructure providers into a solved problem, and enable secure clinical data exchange between mission-critical digital health applications and EHR systems. Datica serves healthcare’s complete spectrum, from digital health startups and industry leaders to health systems across the nation. Hundreds of customers and partners trust Datica to ensure their clouds are HITRUST certified and data securely interoperable. For more information, visit http://www.datica.com.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Catalyze Extends Domain Expertise with Chief Operating Officer Appointment</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press-release/catalyze-extends-domain-expertise-with-chief-operating-officer-appointment"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press-release/catalyze-extends-domain-expertise-with-chief-operating-officer-appointment</id>
    <published>2016-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Brian Lindstrom boosts Catalyze’s growing roster of employees with deep Epic experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;MADISON, WIS. (PRWEB) DECEMBER 14, 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catalyze, healthcare’s go-to source for HIPAA compliant HITRUST CSF Certified hosting and integration services, today announced the appointment of Brian Lindstrom to the role of Chief Operating Officer. In this newly created role, Lindstrom will report to Catalyze CEO Travis Good, MD and help operationalize the vision and strategy for the company’s two main product lines as it expands within the marketplace.
Before joining Catalyze, Lindstrom previously held the role of Chief Financial Officer for Influence Health of Birmingham, Alabama. Considering his Wisconsin roots, he welcomed a return to “the exciting health ecosystem of Madison.” Before Influence Health, Lindstrom spent six years as Controller for Epic, playing a key execution role in Epic’s rapid growth story. He also helped scale the financial group, as well as operationalized Epic’s international business and structured customer contracts during the company’s enormous growth phase. At Catalyze, he will martial this experience to help the company navigate its own growth trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Catalyze has some interesting flagship customers right now and what the company is doing with integrations for those customers is quite unique,” said Lindstrom, Catalyze COO, who expressed excitement about the company’s market-leading cloud platform that offers turnkey, HIPAA compliant hosting and data integration for digital health applications. Compliant cloud hosting enables Catalyze to extend its reach into new markets, such as pharma and payers, which both offer new growth potential for the business. “Catalyze uses managed hosting and integrations to solve interoperability problems that others have yet to solve,” stated Lindstrom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the other six former Epic employees who now work for Catalyze, the sentiment runs parallel to Lindstrom’s. All have an entrepreneurial spirit that flourishes at Catalyze, where the opportunity to build something from the ground up, know how it works and then support it, presents itself daily. These employees also say that they have taken the underlying Epic culture to always do good, while always keeping promises, and have extended that sense of personal honor to how Catalyze treats its own customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The industry insight that emanates from this group of former Epic employees engenders the type of trusted expertise our customers value,” said Catalyze CEO and Chief Privacy Officer Travis Good, MD. “Today, we feel fortunate to add Brian Lindstrom’s financial and operational leadership expertise into the mix.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About Catalyze, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catalyze provides an innovative HIPAA compliant, HITRUST CSF Certified platform with a complete set of modules to handle, store and transmit PHI securely in the cloud. Scalable, HIPAA compliant and interoperable infrastructure is powering the future of healthcare, so Catalyze has built the platform upon which an enterprise can hasten healthcare innovation without the need to become an overnight expert in compliance. For more information, please visit http://www.catalyze.io.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Catalyze Banks on HITRUST CSF Inheritance Program to Make Security Validations Easier for Customers</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press-release/hitrust-csf-inheritance-program-making-security-validations-easier"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press-release/hitrust-csf-inheritance-program-making-security-validations-easier</id>
    <published>2016-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-11-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Catalyze, the compliant cloud infrastructure for healthcare IT development teams, today became one of the first Health Information Trust Alliance (HITRUST) Certified business associates to participate in the HITRUST CSF Inheritance Program.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="catalyze-can-now-willfully-extend-its-hitrust-assessments-to-customers-through-the-program-reducing-costs-and-required-security-testing"&gt;Catalyze can now willfully extend its HITRUST assessments to customers through the program, reducing costs and required security testing.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MADISON, WIS. (PRWEB) NOVEMBER 03, 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catalyze, the compliant cloud infrastructure for healthcare IT development teams, today became one of the first &lt;a href="https://hitrustalliance.net/"&gt;Health Information Trust Alliance&lt;/a&gt; (HITRUST) Certified business associates to participate in the HITRUST CSF Inheritance Program. HITRUST Alliance developed the CSF Inheritance Program and announced its availability in July 2016. The program enables participating service providers that have previously completed the &lt;a href="https://catalyze.io/hitrust"&gt;HITRUST CSF certification process&lt;/a&gt; to allow their customers who are undergoing a HITRUST CSF Assessment to inherit one or more controls from their certified assessment. This reduces the number of controls their customers should need to test as part of their validation process thereby saving them time and money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This extension of security controls comes at a critical time for the healthcare industry. Last June, five of the largest healthcare organizations made HITRUST CSF Certification a future requirement for all business associates. However, a &lt;a href="https://home.kpmg.com/us/en/home/media/press-releases/2016/10/two-thirds-of-business-associates-not-fully-prepared-for-hitrust-healthcare-data-security-standard-kpmg-survey.html"&gt;KPMG HITRUST preparedness industry survey&lt;/a&gt; conducted in August and announced in an October 2016 press release stated, “Two-thirds of business associates are not fully prepared to meet the growing marketplace demands regarding controls for protecting healthcare information, such as patient records.” The survey further indicated that 47 percent of the 600 respondents didn’t have the “right staff with the right level of skills to execute against the HITRUST CSF.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For healthcare IT firms working with a HITRUST CSF Certified business associate, such as Catalyze, this concern is substantially reduced. “Our customers can now leverage security controls from our previous Validated HITRUST CSF assessments in a fully automated manner,” explained Travis Good, MD, Catalyze CEO and Chief Privacy Officer. “This program allows our customers to demonstrate security measures in place to protect their own clients’ healthcare data through the Catalyze infrastructure. The HITRUST Inheritance Program enables those demonstration efforts to happen seamlessly for our customers while reducing costs and a myriad of compliance headaches.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 135 security controls within the HITRUST CSF. Organizations that undergo a HITRUST CSF Validated assessment must use an approved assessor to test each of the controls. The Inheritance Program allows organizations to take advantage of the investments their participating service provider has made in obtaining HITRUST CSF Certification by allowing them to inherit approved controls and not requiring them to be retested. “This is consistent with and supports HITRUST’s objective to reduce redundancy and streamline the compliance process. Why should multiple organizations pay a third party to test the same control requirement?” said Michael Frederick, HITRUST Vice President of Operations. “Companies like Catalyze can leverage the Inheritance Program to provide even greater value to their customers that are tasked with protecting patient information.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Catalyze Raises $6.5 Million in Series B Financing to Meet the Growing Need of Trusted Connectivity within Enterprise Healthcare</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press-release/catalyze-raises-usd6-5-million-in-series-b-financing-to-meet-the-growing"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press-release/catalyze-raises-usd6-5-million-in-series-b-financing-to-meet-the-growing</id>
    <published>2016-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Catalyze raises $6.5 million Series B financing. Lewis &amp;amp; Clark Ventures led the round, joined by existing investors Arthur Ventures, Baird Venture Partners and Chicago Ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;MADISON, WIS. (PRWEB) SEPTEMBER 21, 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catalyze, Inc., healthcare’s leading HITRUST CSF Certified cloud provider, announced today that it has raised $6.5 million in a Series B fundraising effort. St. Louis-based Lewis &amp;amp; Clark Ventures led the round, with participation of existing investors, Arthur Ventures, Baird Venture Partners and Chicago Ventures. The additional financing will allow Catalyze to accelerate growth with its core healthcare integration and hosting products and services. An expanded focus on sales and marketing will broaden efforts toward enterprise customers, such as hospital systems, pharmaceutical companies and payers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catalyze tackled a tough challenge for healthcare development teams by building the first HIPAA compliant infrastructure, called Stratum. During multiple audits of its hosting infrastructure and successful completion of HITRUST CSF Certification, the company solved another challenge for developers with its end-to-end EHR integration product, Redpoint. Through the remainder of this year, Catalyze will solve other real-world problems for the healthcare, as the industry edges closer to value-based care. The challenge will be solved with novel insights through Catalyze, driven by data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The need to empower and enable this healthcare transformation by bringing new and innovative technologies to the industry is something our firm values. As a leader in transformation, Catalyze has built practical solutions to drive healthcare interoperability,” said Brian Hopcraft, managing director of Lewis &amp;amp; Clark Ventures, as well as a newly added Catalyze board member. “We are excited to back Catalyze, a company that has built incredible industry trust and put together a team of skilled professionals who have unmatched expertise that is facilitating a more secure, innovative healthcare system.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest investment round brings total Catalyze funding to more than $12.5 million since inception of its compliant cloud infrastructure. The industry has continued to recognize the company for its market leadership and benchmarks with compliant hosting and EHR integration, naming Catalyze as a semi-finalist for both a TripleTree iAward and an Innovations in Healthcare Abby Award this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s been an exceptional year for Catalyze, with strategic team hires that came with the highest government and enterprise security credentials, an appointment to the first HITRUST Business Associate Council, along with a rapidly expanding roster of customers,” said Catalyze CEO Travis Good, MD. “Those customers have offered our team the unique opportunity to solve a multitude of data exchange challenges that fall outside of traditional standards. With the financial support and domain expertise of Lewis &amp;amp; Clark Ventures and our other investors we look forward to introducing more key healthcare solutions in 2017.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About Catalyze, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catalyze provides an innovative HIPAA compliant, HITRUST CSF Certified platform with a complete set of modules to handle, store and transmit PHI securely in the cloud. Scalable, HIPAA compliant and interoperable infrastructure is powering the future of healthcare, so Catalyze has built the platform upon which an enterprise can hasten healthcare innovation without the need to become an overnight expert in compliance. For more information, please visit http://www.catalyze.io.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Catalyze Delivers HITRUST CSF Certified Compliant Cloud Solutions for Amazon Web Services Workloads</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press-release/catalyze-hitrust-csf-certified-compliant-cloud-solutions-for-aws"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press-release/catalyze-hitrust-csf-certified-compliant-cloud-solutions-for-aws</id>
    <published>2016-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Healthcare customers gain compliance and security measurement with extension of HITRUST CSF Certification Workloads on AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;MADISON, WIS. (PRWEB) JULY 19, 2016&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://catalyze.io"&gt;Catalyze&lt;/a&gt;, a trusted and mature platform for healthcare IT development teams, announced that the company’s compliant cloud platform is now HITRUST CSF Certified for its customers hosting workloads on &lt;a href="https://aws.amazon.com/s/dm/optimization/server-side-test/sem-generic/free-b/?sc_channel=PS&amp;amp;sc_campaign=acquisition_US&amp;amp;sc_publisher=google&amp;amp;sc_medium=cloud_computing_hv_b&amp;amp;sc_content=aws_core_e&amp;amp;sc_detail=amazon%20web%20services&amp;amp;sc_category=cloud_computing&amp;amp;sc_segment=98921920362&amp;amp;sc_matchtype=e&amp;amp;sc_country=US&amp;amp;s_kwcid=AL!4422!3!98921920362!e!!g!!amazon%20web%20services&amp;amp;ef_id=VzSZWwAAAI2yHkPj:20160614203947:s"&gt;Amazon Web Services&lt;/a&gt; (AWS). Catalyze passed its Common Security Framework (CSF) assessment from the Health Information Trust Alliance (HITRUST) — the industry’s benchmark for measuring compliance and security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catalyze, utilizing AWS services and solutions, provides a fully managed Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA) compliant and HITRUST CSF Certified platform for the healthcare industry that offers development teams fast, flexible, and secure access to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Healthcare is an industry in the midst of transitioning to the cloud, and AWS is strategically positioned to service the healthcare industry’s computing needs. AWS’s work with Catalyze, a company that focuses on meeting healthcare’s unique compliance needs through security frameworks like HITRUST, helps position AWS to play a key role in the health industry’s transformation,” said Josh Hofmann, Global Lead, Partner Ecosystem, Amazon Web Services, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Durham-based &lt;a href="http://iscribes.co/"&gt;iScribes&lt;/a&gt;, a Catalyze customer, recognizes the need for such collaboration in securing patient data. “We now process about 36,000 medical charts a month,” said Christopher Kwiatkowski, iScribes Chief Technology Officer. “Without the fast and flexible cloud access from AWS, coupled with Catalyze’s HITRUST CSF Certified compliant layer, our work would be curtailed, significantly more costly, and the patient data we synthesize daily would be at risk.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://catalyze.io/compliance"&gt;Healthcare compliance&lt;/a&gt; presents a challenge for development teams. Minneapolis-based Zipnosis has experienced those challenges as it has scaled its virtual care technology. “Healthcare IT developers leverage the collaboration of AWS and its AWS Partner Network (APN) partners like Catalyze, so the unique compliance needs of the industry are addressed and supported,” said Derek Rockwell, Zipnosis’ Director of Engineering. “We have been using AWS for five years, been working with Catalyze for three years, and the relationship has allowed us to further consolidate, secure, and optimize our infrastructure — giving us a significant edge.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Affirmation of Catalyze’s second HITRUST CSF Certification assessment of its platform, with an extension to AWS workloads provides customers with the following benefits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easier management of federal, state, and third-party security regulations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A simplified method to showcase a company as a trustworthy resource&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Additional assurance that a company meets and exceeds the minimum requirements of Health Insurance  Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The HITRUST Common Security Framework provides an efficient and prescriptive guideline for managing the security requirements found within HIPAA and one for which Catalyze customers have found great value. “The time, effort and expertise required for compliance is often more than our customers want to tackle themselves,” explained Catalyze President Mohan Balachandran. “A majority of our customers already use AWS as their cloud infrastructure of choice, so the extension of our HITRUST CSF Certification to include AWS workloads is beneficial for them.”&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Catalyze Extends Trust, Security and Privacy Commitment with Second HITRUST CSF Certification Assessment</title>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://datica.com/press-release/catalyze-extends-trust-security-and-privacy-commitment-with-second-hitrust"/>
    <id>https://datica.com/press-release/catalyze-extends-trust-security-and-privacy-commitment-with-second-hitrust</id>
    <published>2016-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2016-06-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
      <name>Marcia Noyes</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Catalyze, Inc., announced today that the company has gained the Health Information Trust Alliance (HITRUST) stamp of approval on its second and interim Common Security Framework (CSF) assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id="digital-health-company-broadens-hitrust-certification-to-include-each-of-its-four-cloud-infrastructure-partners"&gt;Digital health company broadens HITRUST Certification to include each of its four cloud infrastructure partners.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Madison, Wis. (PRWEB) June 09, 2016&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catalyze, Inc., the healthcare industry’s trusted and mature platform for healthcare IT development teams, announced today that the company has gained the Health Information Trust Alliance (HITRUST) stamp of approval on its second and interim Common Security Framework (CSF) assessment. This HITRUST status expands the scope of HITRUST CSF Certification to include additional cloud providers for Stratum, Catalyze’s hosting platform, as well as for Redpoint, their integration product. In addition to Rackspace®, Catalyze’s original infrastructure partner, the expanded certification includes AWS (Amazon), Azure™ (Microsoft) and SoftLayer® (IBM) cloud offerings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compliance continues to increase in complexity. As technologies evolve to store and transfer increasing amounts of healthcare data, providers face an overwhelming task of managing security requirements from federal and state agencies, as well as other third parties. That encompassing concern heightens by the rise in healthcare data breaches. Accordingly, the HITRUST Alliance developed a clear, secure and efficient system to clarify the complexities and often vague language found within the Health Information Portability and Accountability Act (HIPAA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations that meet the stringent HITRUST CSF control requirements are more suitably prepped to secure confidential data and manage healthcare’s convoluted regulatory environments. Catalyze CTO &amp;amp; Security Officer Adam Leko said it also speaks to “the breadth of Catalyze’s compliance approach.” Beyond meeting HIPAA’s generic requirements, the HITRUST CSF Certification is “a security framework with great detail and depth that is spreading wider in terms of industry adoption,” according to Leko.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital health company HealthLoop, a Catalyze customer, shared similar thoughts about the importance of HITRUST CSF Certification. “Many vendors and cloud companies tout compliance, but since HIPAA regulations do not provide specific standards, health systems have to spend a lot of time evaluating the level of standards being met. A HIPAA-compliant vendor that only minimally meets standards could be a huge exposure risk,” explained Mayank Thanawala, HealthLoop’s CTO.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In June 2015, the HITRUST Alliance announced that five of the largest U.S. healthcare payers would make HITRUST CSF Certification mandatory from business associates (BAs) within the coming 24 months. Meeting and ensuring HIPAA security rule mandates, ultimately lessens the payers’ compliance burdens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leko shared that HITRUST CSF Certification and the subsequent recertification of all of the company’s cloud infrastructure partners are a substantial competitive checkpoint to reach. “The third-party verification shows that Catalyze continues to perform exceptionally well, both in meeting the core requirements for HITRUST and in general with securing patient information. Gaining industry verification for our processes, procedures and policies makes the time and effort in obtaining the certification a worthwhile investment.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to the roughly year-long process to gain initial HITRUST CSF Certification, recertification moved along more rapidly with completion in three and a half months. Leko stated, “While I credit our auditor Coalfire℠ for their thoroughness and hard work, I’m especially pleased with how quickly HITRUST turned around our assessment evaluation and approval.”&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
